If you collect 99 devil's keys,
只要集齐99把恶魔钥匙
you can have everything in the world.
就能在世界上呼风唤雨
The mysterious organization Gungnir is holding an ACMA:GAME tournament.
神秘组织永恒之枪举办了一个 ACMA：GAME恶魔游戏锦标赛
Who is this Guide?
那个引领者是谁？
You should show respect when you speak his name.
请不要随便提引领者大人的名字
What has Gungnir done to you?
永恒之枪对你做了什么？
I think I might have found Gungnir's hideout.
我可能找到永恒之枪的隐匿地点了
What the hell?
为什么？
Get up here quickly before you fall.
不想受伤就赶快上来
Hurry!
快啊
You're out of your mind.
你真是胡闹
Why are you here?
你怎么会在这里？
Did Hoshin tell you to spy on me?
崩心派你来监视我吗？
Do you want to know more about the keys and Gungnir's Guide?
你想知道钥匙和引领者的信息吗？
Then come with me.
想知道就跟我来
What do you mean?
什么意思？
What are you hiding?
你藏着什么目的？
Let's speak while we walk.
边走边说吧
A drone will find us if we stay here.
在这里会被无人机发现
A while back, things were going badly for the company.
不久前我在工作上遇到了一些不顺
I was drowning in it all, when a key fell in front of me.
在我焦头烂额时 一把钥匙掉落在我面前
After that, Hoshin called to tell me about the tournament.
之后不久 崩心给我打电话 说了锦标赛的事
He said you'd be playing too.
他说你也会参加
I guessed you accepted the invitation
我猜你接受比赛要求
to avenge your father's death.
是为了给父亲报仇
So I pretended to be consumed by greed
所以我假装被欲望吞噬
to get closer to Hoshin and find out more.
以便接近崩心 查出更多线索
I confided in Yuki a while ago.
我刚才已经跟悠季坦白
So…
所以说…
I didn't betray you.
我没有背叛你
Before I came here, and since I've been here,
不管是来这里之前 还是之后
I've always been on your side.
我都一直站在你这边
The second match of round two is about to begin.
第二轮第二场比赛即将开始
-Players are asked… -Yuki's next?
-请参赛者… -悠季要比赛了？
-…to move to… -If anything happens…
-…前往 -如果出什么事
-…the game room. -…I hope Senya will help her.
-…游戏室 -希望潜夜能帮她
Brother,
哥哥
why didn't you save me?
你为什么不救我？
Senya,
潜夜
why are you the only one who survived?
为什么只有你可以活下来？
You're alive for nothing.
你活得没有一点用处
You'll be alone forever.
你将永远孤独一人
-Brother, brother… -Senya!
-哥哥… -潜夜
Not again.
又来了
Senya, it's me.
潜夜君 是我
I want to win this.
我想赢下这个比赛
I want to be like Ui, and help Teruasa.
我想像初君一样帮照朝
Ui? Isn't he a traitor?
初？他不是叛徒吗？
You've got it backwards.
恰恰相反
He was on our side.
他一直站在我们这边
He's searching for Gungnir with Teruasa right now.
现在他正和照朝君 搜寻永恒之枪的窝点
Hoshin.
崩心
The Guide could be in there.
引领者可能在里面
There are no surveillance cameras.
这里没有监控摄像头
Come on.
走吧
-He's happy. -Having fun?
-他很开心 -玩得开心吗？
-He's having fun. -He's in a good mood.
-玩得很开心 -他心情不错
-Here we go. -Look.
-来 -看
Face this way.
看这边
-Look! -He's smiling. So cute.
-他笑了 真可爱
Daddy can't stop filming you, can he?
爸爸总是拍个不停 对吧？
KING
（王将）
I win.
我会赢的
I always win.
一定会赢
Mori was Dragon King at 19 years old. He must be a genius.
毛利是19岁就成为龙王的天才棋手
A genius, huh?
天才？
But Date said he's only held on to his title because of the key.
但伊达说 他是靠恶魔钥匙才得到这个称号的
It's true that he lost a game once,
他确实输过一次
and apparently at one point he couldn't play shogi at all.
然后有一段时间 他完全无法下将棋
Really?
嗯？
But since he got the key he's been on a winning streak.
但自从他得到钥匙后 到现在一直是连胜状态
He'll be a tough opponent.
他是一个劲敌
Sorry, Mori. Are you okay?
不好意思 毛利 你没事吧？
Here.
来
Now don't get cross.
别生气嘛
I'll get outta your way.
我给你让路
Let's go, Yukky.
走吧 小悠季
Sorry.
不好意思
Is that Mori's phone?
这是毛利的手机吗？
Yep, you got it.
嗯 对啊
You're a thief. Give it back!
这不是小偷行径吗？快还回去
If we wanna win, we need information on the enemy.
要是想赢 就得获取敌人的情报
But－
可是…
Nice to see you, my friends.
各位 你们好啊
I'm sorry we're late.
抱歉来迟了
It's the second match of round two of the ACMA:GAME tournament.
现在即将举行ACMA：GAME锦标赛 第二轮第二场的比赛
The battle between Uesugi's team and Mori's team begins.
上杉队将对战毛利队
The only thing at stake is the right to each other's lives.
赌注是彼此生命的掌控权
I can't wait to see the results.
我对比赛结果非常期待
Okay.
好
Shall we start?
可以开始了吗？
Can I summon the devil?
我来召唤恶魔可以吗？
Give my phone back first.
在此之前 请先把手机还给我
What? What do you mean?
你说什么？
You took it when you bumped into me.
你撞上我时拿了我的手机
It's here.
在这里
-Hey, wait. -Sorry.
-等等 -不好意思
Yukky. Are you kidding me?
小悠季 你怎么这样？
Did you see it?
你看了吗？
So what if we did?
我们看了又怎么样？
Even a sour-faced grouch like you gets all cutesy around the family.
你虽然总是板着个脸 但在家人面前却充满了柔情
Hope they're not gonna be taken hostage like Yukky's family was.
希望他们 没有像小悠季的家人一样被劫持
Don't worry. My wife and son are safe at home.
我的妻儿都好好地在家里 不用担心
I came here by choice.
我是自愿来这里的
To make sure I win
为了获胜
and get the keys.
和得到钥匙
I see.
好的
Have you met Gungnir's Guide?
你见过那个引领者吗？
No.
没有
Unfortunately, I haven't even seen what he looks like.
很遗憾 我没见过他的样子
But I did find out something about him.
但我发现了关于他的一些信息
The Guide and I have been acquaintances for over ten years.
我和引领者有超过十年的交情
Ten years ago was around the time
十年前恰好是
of the Oda group case, wasn't it?
织田集团出事的时间
Yes.
对
Our Guide instructed us to do that too.
那也是引领者安排我们做的
The Guide was the one who attacked my father?
果然是那个引领者害死父亲的
Yoo-hoo, El-chin.
小埃埃
Can you make it a game that suits teams, El-chin?
如果你能安排一个适合团体赛的游戏 那就太好了
I shall gladly comply with the wishes
那我埃尔瓦 就满足愚蠢和下等的人类
of you silly, lowly humans.
让你们如愿
Senya and Mori,
潜夜先生 毛利先生
what do each of you demand?
你们有什么要求？
I want the right to do whatever I like with their lives.
我要自由掌控他们生命的权利
Same for me.
我也一样
I accept your requests.
我同意你们的要求
This time, the game is called…
这次的游戏是
"Clay Dialogue"?
粘土问答？
This game is played using clay.
这个比赛要使用粘土
Clay?
粘土？
I love it already.
听起来有意思
There are four turns in each set.
比赛的每一局分为四个环节
First, it's the question turn.
第一个环节是“出题”
One person from the first team goes through the door,
第一队的一个人走到门后面
and writes a theme on the paper.
在纸上写一个题目
The theme must be a common, tangible noun.
题目必须是不过于专业的具体名词
A tangible noun.
具体名词
So, like, "poop," or, "poop"?
比如便便？
You love poop, don't you?
你就这么喜欢便便？
The time limit for the question turn is ten seconds.
出题时间为十秒
A game with time limits, huh?
原来是有时间限制的比赛
Next, the teams switch,
然后换另一队
and the production turn begins.
进入到“制作”环节
One person on the opposing team
另一队的一名选手
checks the theme chosen by the first team,
查看第一队出的题目
and tries to mold it with the clay.
然后用粘土把题目呈现出来
The time limit is 60 seconds.
这个环节的时间限制是60秒
What? Only 60 seconds?
啊？才60秒？
You can only communicate the theme by using clay.
你们只能通过粘土沟通题目信息
Can we write letters in the clay?
可以在粘土上写字吗？
You may.
可以写字
However, there is a risk that the letters will be erased in the obstacles turn.
但是在“妨害”环节 你们写的字可能会被抹掉
In the obstacles turn,
在“妨害”环节
the second person from the team who chose the theme
出题队伍的第二名选手
is allowed to mess up the clay sculpture to make the theme unrecognizable.
可以对粘土动手脚 让人看不出原题
The time limit is 20 seconds.
这个环节的时间限制是20秒
Well, makes sense.
原来如此
The final turn is the answer turn.
最后一个环节是回答环节
In the answer turn,
在回答环节
the second player from the team who created the clay sculpture
捏粘土队伍的第二个选手
looks at the messed up clay,
观察被动过手脚的粘土
and guesses the theme originally chosen by the other team.
然后猜另一队原本出了什么题
Those who guess the theme perfectly score one point.
猜中者得一分
Incorrect guessers get nothing.
猜错者不得分
Both teams take turns to play six sets.
两队依次交换顺序 一共比六局
At the end, the player with the highest number of points is the winner.
最后得分更多的队伍获胜
Can you do whatever you want outside the door?
我们在门外做什么都可以吗？
To make sure you don't give the answer away during the set,
为了避免你们在比赛期间交流答案
the other players will lose their sight, hearing, smell, touch, and taste.
候场的选手将失去 视觉、听觉、嗅觉、触觉和味觉
In other words, all five senses are suppressed.
也就是说 你们的五感将会被封印
-In total darkness? -Yes.
-完全黑暗的意思？ -对
And no sound?
没有声音？
None.
没有
Oh, right.
好吧
Mori's team will begin the question round,
现在由毛利队先出题
and start the game!
比赛开始
CLAY DIALOGUE SET 1
（粘土问答 第一局）
Remaining players, your senses will be suppressed,
其余选手 你们的五感将会被封印
so please take your seats.
请到椅子上坐好
Senya, that includes you. Please be seated.
潜夜先生 请你也入座
Fine.
好的
You will now lose all five senses.
现在封印五感
I really can't see a thing.
真的什么都看不见
Or hear anything.
什么都听不见
No smell either.
也闻不到气味
SET 1 QUESTION
（第一局 出题）
Cool.
好厉害
Asai,
浅井先生
write down a theme.
请写出题目
You have ten seconds.
你有十秒钟
Gotta think of something impossible.
我得尽量出比较难的题
Hamburger? Steak? Mont Blanc? I have no idea.
汉堡？牛排？勃朗峰？怎么办
Five seconds have passed.
时间已过五秒钟
Oh, shit.
糟糕
Done.
好了
Good work, Asai.
浅井先生 辛苦了
Your senses will be suppressed. Please sit.
你的五感将会被封印 请入座
What? That's so annoying.
什么？好讨厌呀
This is creepy.
这好可怕
Shit, this is gonna feel weird－
哎呀 感觉好奇怪…
Yuki, please go through the door.
悠季小姐 请走进那道门
Sheesh, this could be bad.
糟糕了
SET 1 PRODUCTION
（第一局 制作）
You have 60 seconds to produce something.
你有60秒的制作时间
A dog? Way too easy.
“犬”？这个题目很简单
Five seconds have passed.
时间已过五秒钟
Wait, does it actually look like a dog?
等等 这看起来真的像狗吗？
Doesn't it look like a cow or a pig?
看起来会不会像牛或猪？
It's way more difficult than I thought to make it look like a dog.
把它弄得像一只狗 比我想象的难多了
Thirty seconds have passed.
时间已过30秒钟
I know.
有了
He looks in pain, even though all his senses are blocked.
虽然他的五感被封印了 但他却显得很痛苦
Why?
为什么呢？
Well done, Yuki.
悠季小姐 辛苦了
Your senses will be suppressed. Please sit.
你的五感将会被封印 请入座
Okay.
好的
Mori, it's time for the obstacles turn.
毛利先生 轮到你进行妨害了
Please go through the door.
请走进那道门
SET 1 OBSTACLES
（第一局 妨害）
So it's a dog and a kennel?
这是狗和犬舍？
Mori, you have 20 seconds to mess up the clay sculpture.
毛利先生 你有20秒钟破坏粘土作品
-Why didn't you save me? -Senya,
-你为什么不救我？ -潜夜
-why are you the only one who survived? -Senya.
-为什么只有你可以活下来？
Senya!
潜夜
It's the answer turn. Please go through the door.
接下来是回答环节 请走进那道门
Right.
好
You look a bit pale.
你的脸色很不好
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
SET 1 ANSWER
（第一局 回答）
Please say what you think the theme is.
请猜猜题目是什么
There is no time limit for this round,
这个环节没有时间限制
so please think carefully.
请好好考虑再回答
Here goes.
好
For real?
哎？
Well, well. What are you going to do next?
好啊 接下来你打算怎么做？
The clay is rock solid.
这粘土硬邦邦的
The clay is designed to harden after a certain period of time.
超过时间限制后 粘土会自动变硬
All of it?
全部都会变吗？
No exception?
没有例外？
Does that include the clay that doesn't get used?
没用过的粘土也有时间限制吗？
No.
没有
Any clay that wasn't used to create a sculpture won't harden.
陈列桌上的粘土 如果未使用它们来制作雕塑
It can still be reshaped.
那么土不会变硬
Then what is this?
那这会是什么呢？
A dog
一只狗
and a kennel?
和一个犬舍？
And Mori has already tried to sabotage this, right?
毛利对它们做过手脚 对吧？
Indeed.
没错
So which bit did Mori add on?
那么有一个是毛利加的吗？
Why does the roof only stick out at the back?
为什么只有后面有屋檐？
He just flattened one side?
他把一侧压平了？
That must be it.
原来如此 我看出来了
I can see where Mori tried to trick me.
我看穿了毛利的误导
Reasoning invites doubt, leading one far from the answer.
推理会引起怀疑 将答案越推越远
That's my strategy.
这就是我的作战策略
I'm alive.
活过来了
Senya, it's time to answer.
潜夜先生 请回答
My answer is…
我的答案是…
house.
房子
Senya,
潜夜先生
incorrect!
回答错误
You're kidding?
什么？
The answer is, "dog."
答案是“犬”
Dog?
犬？
Senya's team scores zero.
潜夜队不得分
Then why is there only an overhang at the back?
那房子为什么只在后面有屋檐？
To convey a dog,
为了表达“犬”这个题目
first, Yuki simply made a dog.
悠季小姐先是捏了一只狗
But she lost confidence once she saw the result.
但是她看到成品后感觉不自信
She probably thought you might think it was a different animal.
她可能觉得你会猜成其他动物
So she made something else associated with a dog.
所以她捏了一个跟狗有关的东西
Done!
好了
A dog kennel.
也就是一个犬舍
When I saw it, I got thinking.
我看到时就在想
What small change could I make to the kennel to mislead you?
我可以在犬舍上做什么小改动 以误导你？
Eaves on one side.
于是我制作了单侧的屋檐
Just as I predicted, you misinterpreted that small change.
如我所料 你看到那个小改变后 就开始推理了
You decided the dog was a decoy.
你以为狗是我制造的干扰
So the answer couldn't be, "dog,"
所以你觉得答案不会是犬舍
but must be, "house."
而是房子
You're better at this than I thought.
你确实比我想的要厉害
But you fell
但你掉入了
straight into the trap I set for you.
我设的圈套
My bad.
真遗憾啊
This guy is bad news.
这家伙还真厉害
Senya, can I speak to you?
潜夜 借一步说话
Yeah.
好
Did you see Mori just now?
你看到毛利的样子了吗？
He gives me the heebie-jeebies.
他让我很有压力
You looked like you were struggling earlier. Is everything okay?
刚才你看起来很痛苦 没事吧？
I'm totally fine.
没这种事
You must be seeing things.
你一定是看错了
We're on the same team. You shouldn't hide anything from me.
我们现在是团队作战 有事不要瞒着我
I promise I'm fine.
我真的什么事都没有
Shall we?
好 继续吧
It's my turn to choose a theme.
轮到我出题了
What are those markings?
那些记号是什么意思？
An attack.
侵略
Military invasion.
军事侵略
Revolution.
革命
Coup d'etat.
政变
They look like
这些可能是
current conflict zones across the world.
当今世界上有冲突的地带
Why are they logging conflict zones?
他们为什么要记录冲突地带？
And that star.
那颗星星
"Eliminate G20 from this world."
“消灭世界二十国集团”
What does it mean?
那是什么意思？
Key locations?
（小笠原群岛 18 加勒比海 14）
The locations with the most keys are
拥有最多钥匙的位置是
the Caribbean,
加勒比地区
the Aegean Sea,
爱琴海
and off the Ogasawara Islands.
和小笠原群岛附近
This island is probably there.
这里可能就位于群岛中
They find information on the key owners
他们收集了钥匙持有者的信息
and enter them into the tournament.
然后让他们参加锦标赛
Then,
那么
why mark the conflict zones?
他们为什么要标记冲突地带？
Could it be that?
会是那个吗？
SET 2 ANSWER
（第二局 回答）
Mori, it's time for you to answer.
毛利先生 请回答
My answer is "valley".
我的答案是“山谷”
Incorrect!
不正确
The correct answer is, "hill."
正确答案是“山丘”
Shit!
该死的
That was a malicious sabotage.
你们的妨害真卑鄙
You're welcome.
不客气
It's zero points each.
现在比分是0比0
Ui, Gungnir have 50 keys, don't they?
初 永恒之枪有50把钥匙 对吧？
Yes.
对
So the aim of this tournament is to take our keys.
这个锦标赛的目的 是夺走我们的钥匙
If Gungnir takes ours, they will have 99.
如果永恒之枪夺走我们的钥匙 他们就一共有99把
By bringing conflict and destruction to the current world,
他们让世界纷争四起 破坏不停
they intend to create a new one.
是为了要打造一个新世界
But then why wouldn't they just take the keys by force?
那么他们为什么 不直接用武力夺走钥匙？
Why bother making us compete in the games?
为什么要费心让我们在比赛中竞争？
I don't know.
我不知道
I don't know why they're making us compete in ACMA:GAME.
我不知道他们为什么 让我们参加ACMA：GAME游戏
But…
但是…
the total number of keys between us in this tournament is 18.
在这个锦标赛中 我们参赛者的钥匙一共有18把
But there are 57 keys on this island.
但岛上一共有57把钥匙
So Gungnir's keys are on this island.
所以永恒之枪的钥匙在这个岛上
And somewhere else,
还有一个地方
there's a place with 11 keys.
藏了11把钥匙
The Guide?
引领者？
Yes.
对
The Guide is moving the rest of Gungnir's keys.
引领者携带 永恒之枪的其余钥匙在移动
It's on route to Japan.
他的目的地是日本
He's coming here?
难道他要来这里？
Many people will die if we let this go on.
这样下去 很多人会丧命
It'll be a blood bath.
血流成河
We need to find the rest of the keys and destroy them.
我们要找到其余的钥匙 把它们摧毁
I have to stop them from getting what they want.
我要阻止他们实现企图
SET 3 ANSWER
（第三局 回答）
The answer is "clay".
答案是“粘土”
Senya.
潜夜先生
CLAY
（粘土）
Correct!
回答正确
We did it!
太好了
SET 4 ANSWER
（第四局 回答）
The answer is "tile".
答案是“瓦片”
Mori.
毛利先生
TILE
（瓦片）
-You're correct! -Take that!
-回答正确 -太好了
Smashed it!
得分了
We're tied.
分数相同
Hey, Mori.
毛利
I have a little suggestion.
我有个小建议
In the last two rounds, why don't we switch the order?
在最后两局 我们换顺序怎么样？
I really don't care,
我倒是不介意
but you won't win with dirty tricks.
但耍小聪明是赢不了的
Okay with you, El-chin?
可以吗 小埃埃？
I approve.
我同意
I just need more time.
我需要时间
I've almost got it.
我很快就能找到
A foolproof way to beat him.
制胜他的办法
Teruasa, Hoshin's on his way here.
照朝 崩心过来了
Hurry.
快
If we use a drone, we can track down Ui and Teruasa－
如果使用无人机 可以追踪齐藤初和织田照朝…
No, no.
不必
We don't need to find them.
不需要追踪
It's a waste of time.
那只是浪费时间
SET 5 ANSWER
（第五局 回答）
Mori, what's your answer?
毛利先生 请回答
My answer is "house".
我的回答是“房子”
HOUSE
（房子）
Correct!
回答正确
Yes! We've won!
太好了 赢啦
Now for the final set.
现在是最终局
The question setter must go through the door.
出题人请走进那道门
Bring it on!
加油
Crap, we can't get ahead.
糟糕 没能领先
No matter what, we need to get a draw in this set.
这一局无论如何都要打成平局
Then we will win next.
然后在下一局赢他们
Yukky.
小悠季
The next problem is…
下一道题是…
how long will I last in the darkness?
我能在黑暗中撑多久？
All five senses will be blocked.
现在封印五感
Teruasa!
照朝
Yukari, who won the game?
紫 谁赢了？
It's not finished yet.
还没结束
Anyway, where did you go? I was looking for you.
但是你去哪里了？我一直在找你
I stole devil's keys hidden by Gungnir.
我偷了永恒之枪藏的钥匙
-What? Seriously? -Yes.
-啊？真的吗？ -对
There aren't any keys in here.
这里面没有钥匙
That's not possible.
那不可能
They disappeared?
它们消失了？
Yukari,
紫
play ACMA:GAME with me.
跟我玩ACMA：GAME恶魔游戏
What?
啊？
I hate what comes to me in the quiet.
在安静中 即使我不喜欢 那些事也会涌出来
Regret and loneliness wash over me again and again.
后悔和孤独一遍又一遍冲刷着我
October 23rd, 2015.
2015年10月23日
When I got home in the night, my home was destroyed,
我夜晚回家时 发现家里一片狼藉
and my mother and sister had stopped moving, like broken dolls.
妈妈和妹妹就像坏了的洋娃娃 一动不动
Senya!
潜夜先生
The color is draining from your face.
你的脸色真的很不好
Time for the production turn of the final set.
请进行最终局的制作环节
FINAL SET PRODUCTION
（最终局 制作）
"Water."
水
Water doesn't have a fixed shape.
水没有固定的形状
A pond, river, puddle,
池水、河水、积水
a cup of juice, plumbing.
一杯果汁 管道中的水
This is a really tough one.
这道题非常难
But it doesn't matter.
但没关系
I'll use this hiding place and my power.
我有必胜的隐秘之境
It's a foolproof plan.
和无敌的恶魔之力
Time's up.
时间到
Senya, stop whatever you're doing.
潜夜先生 请停手
I didn't want to have to use it.
如果可以的话 我不想用恶魔之力
But I have no choice.
但现在没办法了
Mori, it's time for the obstacles turn.
毛利先生 请开始进行妨害
Please go through the door.
请进入那道门
Sorry, Mori.
抱歉了 毛利
I'm going to hit you where it hurts.
从现在开始 我要攻击你最脆弱的地方
You'll regret letting me unleash my ability.
你会后悔让我使用恶魔之力的
FINAL SET OBSTACLES
（最终局 妨害）
It's you!
老公
Shizu? How did you get here?
静 你怎么在这里？
Where am I?
这是哪里？
We were at home, then suddenly we were here.
我们原本在家里的 然后突然就到这里了
Devil power.
恶魔之力
You have 20 seconds to mess up the clay sculpture.
你有20秒的时间对粘土作品动手脚
What's that? Whose voice was that? Hey, you!
什么？那是什么声音？老公
This is bad.
情况不妙
My devil power is Super Delivery.
我的恶魔之力是“超级快递”
Also called Rapid Retrieval.
也叫“超快送达”
As long as I know where it is,
只要我知道目标在哪里
I can bring in anything from outside the sealed room.
就能把它们从外面 移动到封闭空间里
No matter how formidable Mori may be,
不管毛利有多难对付
the sudden appearance of his dear family will confuse him,
他看到亲爱的家人出现 一定会方寸大乱
and before he knows it, his time will be up.
他的时间将会转瞬即逝
What a pity I can't watch as your face gets all flustered.
看不到你惊慌失措的表情真遗憾啊
What is this place?
这是什么地方？
You've been away for days.
你几天不在家
What are you doing here?
在这里做什么？
Answer me!
不要沉默 快告诉我
Ten seconds have passed.
时间已过十秒钟
I can't mess this up now.
我不能在这里拖拖拉拉
What?
哎？
It's the answer turn.
接下来是回答环节
Yuki, go through the door,
悠季小姐 请进入那道门
look at the clay sculpture, and make your guess.
观察粘土作品 然后猜题目是什么
Could that woman holding the baby be Mori's family?
那个抱小孩的女人 可能是毛利的家人
I don't know how they got here,
不知道他们是怎么来这里的
but Senya used his devil power.
但潜夜使用了他的恶魔之力
Mori must have been in shock.
毛利一定很惊讶
He didn't have time to think and made a mess of the clay.
他肯定没能好好思考 和破坏粘土作品
But it's fine.
不过没关系
The answer isn't here.
答案不在这里
The correct answer is over here.
正确答案在这里
Here!
在这里
Inside the clay.
答案在粘土里
The clay on the main table
主桌上的粘土
hardens at the end of the turn, and can't be modified.
会在回合结束后硬化 无法再塑型
But the clay on the workshop table is different.
但是陈列桌上的粘土不一样
However much time passes, the clay stays soft.
不管时间过去多久 它们都是软的
Found it.
找到了
Mog chocolate?
Mog巧克力？
I'll bet this Mog chocolate on a game with Yukari.
我赌上这颗Mog巧克力 和紫玩游戏
Understood.
知道了
-Then let the game－ -But first,
-那就开始… -在此之前…
I have some questions.
我有几件事想问你
What do you want to know?
你想知道什么？
I stole the devil's keys in Gungnir's possession, but they disappeared.
我偷了永恒之枪持有的恶魔钥匙 但它们消失了
Where did they go?
这些钥匙去哪里了？
Unless the owner passes them on,
除非是持有者转让
or you beat the owner at ACMA:GAME,
或是在ACMA：GAME恶魔游戏中 战胜持有者
devil's keys cannot be moved.
否则恶魔钥匙无法转移
So the keys were returned to that room.
所以钥匙回到了那个房间
It appears that the finals at the other venues have finished.
其他会场的决赛已经结束
I see.
好的
Sorry to bother you. The Guide will arrive shortly.
打扰了 引领者大人马上就到
I'm coming.
我这就去迎接
What's happening?
这是…
FINAL SET ANSWER
（最终局 回答）
Yuki, it is time for you to answer.
悠季小姐 请回答
My answer is…
我的答案是…
ice.
冰
Yuki.
悠季小姐
Incorrect!
回答错误
Take that!
太好了
The correct answer is, "water."
正确答案是水
Therefore, the winner of Clay Dialogue
因此“粘土问答”的胜者是
is Mori's team!
毛利队
What happened, Yukky?
怎么回事 小悠季？
Did he find the hiding place?
他发现了你藏的粘土？
You wrote the answer in the middle of the soft clay.
你把答案 写在不会随时间硬化的粘土中
I had the same idea.
这和我想的办法一样
But I was surprised.
但我很惊讶
My wife and son were behind that door.
我的妻儿竟然出现在那道门后
I guess you summoned them here with your devil power.
我猜你用了恶魔之力 把他们召唤过来吧？
But you should have lost your shit, and the ability to reason calmly.
但你应该失去理智 无法冷静做出判断才对
Twenty seconds should have flown by!
20秒应该转瞬即逝才对
So, is this your wife and baby?
所以这是你的妻子和孩子？
I'm Mori's wife, Shizu.
我是毛利的妻子 静
Nice to meet you.
我先生承蒙您照顾了
It's lovely to meet you too－
彼此彼此 承蒙关照
Wait, what?
哎？
What was that for?
你这是干什么？
Hold on one second, your wife and child are right here.
等等 你的妻儿在这里
Seems so.
是啊
I mean, like, right here.
不可思议 他们竟然在这里
What the hell?
为什么？
How can you be so calm?
你怎么能这么平静？
Stop it, Senya.
不要这样 潜夜
You were reunited with your family.
你好不容易跟家人团聚
How can you ignore them like that?
怎么能这样若无其事？
Isn't family more important to you?
家人对你来说不是更重要吗?
Winning
获胜
is my one and only priority.
对我来说大于一切
Winning is more important to me than my family.
获胜比我的家人更重要
You're disgusting!
开什么玩笑！
Don't speak to my husband like that.
不要这么粗暴地跟我丈夫说话
What?
但是…
The most valuable thing to Mori is winning a serious game.
对我丈夫来说 最重要的是 在真刀真枪的比赛中获胜
That's what my husband lives for.
这是我丈夫人生观
You can have your own values and ideas of happiness,
你可以有自己的价值观 和衡量幸福的尺度
but please don't impose them on us.
但不要把它强加给我们
When they appeared,
看到他们突然出现
I lost my concentration.
我确实乱了阵脚
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Answer me!
不要沉默 快告诉我
Ten seconds have passed.
时间已过十秒钟
I can't mess this up now.
我不能在这里拖拖拉拉
I'm in the middle of a game! Go away!
静 不要打扰我比赛
Akira－
老公
Shut Out.
“排除”
Also known as Distraction Elimination.
也叫“知觉消去”
It's a devil power that makes a chosen object
这个恶魔之力可以让我的五感
imperceptible to the senses until the end of the game.
在游戏结束之前 感觉不到指定目标的存在
I had a few seconds left.
我还剩几秒钟
Just enough to change the kanji from "water" to "ice".
这足以让我将“水”改成“冰”
Now we must settle the bets.
现在清算赌注
Mori now has the right to do as he wishes with your lives,
潜夜先生和悠季小姐的性命
Senya and Yuki.
归毛利先生掌控
All devil's keys in Senya's possession,
潜夜先生持有的所有钥匙
fall into Mori's hands.
归毛利先生所有
This brings the game Clay Dialogue to an end.
“粘土问答”游戏到此结束
Until we meet again.
下次再会
Thank you.
谢谢
That was quite the game,
这是一场酣畅淋漓的比赛
Senya.
潜夜
Akira.
老公
Sorry for brushing you aside during the game.
抱歉在比赛中无视你
Isamu,
小勇
I've missed you.
爸爸想你了
Sorry, Yukky.
抱歉 小悠季
I lost it.
我输了
Why are you apologizing?
你为什么要道歉？
I'm the one who should be sorry.
该道歉的人是我
You were in pain throughout the game,
你在比赛时一直很痛苦
and there's nothing I could do.
而我却什么都做不了
I'm meant to be your friend.
我真把你当朋友
Senya, Yuki.
潜夜 悠季
Teruasa.
照朝君
Who are they?
那是…
Senya.
潜夜
Sorry, Terurin.
抱歉 小照照
I couldn't keep my promise.
我食言了
The game isn't over yet.
游戏还没结束
I'm no use to you anymore.
我已经毫无用处了
That's not true.
没那回事
Have you forgotten?
你忘了吗？
You made a bet against me.
你跟我打过赌
So help me finish this.
所以帮我到最后一刻吧
If I'm going to destroy all of the keys, I'll need your help.
如果要摧毁所有钥匙 我需要你的帮助
Guess I'm outta options.
真是没办法啊
Looks like I'm gonna be stuck with you a little longer.
我再陪你一阵时间吧
Wait there.
等等
You're worse than Gungnir.
你比永恒之枪还可怕
What we gonna do if you destroy the keys? They're worth everything to me.
你要是摧毁了钥匙 我们怎么办？ 其他东西可没那种价值
More than a person's life?
你觉得钥匙比人命重要？
That's totally irrelevant－
这两个不是一回事
They want the keys to take the lives of huge numbers of people.
他们想用钥匙夺走无数人的性命
We're just pawns in their game.
我们只是他们的棋子
What?
啊？
Take lives?
夺走性命？
I went to their hideout.
我去了他们的窝点
There was information on the key owners,
那里有钥匙持有者的信息
and a world map marked with conflict zones.
还有标出冲突地带的世界地图
What Gungnir describes as "creating a new world,"
永恒之枪所谓的“打造新世界”
means taking our keys to create an even bigger war.
就是夺取我们的钥匙 然后发动更大规模的战争
Why bother with a tournament when they could just take the keys?
他们可以直接夺走钥匙 何必费劲举办锦标赛？
You can't take the keys by force.
因为不能靠武力夺取钥匙
Unless the owner passes them on,
除非是持有者转让
or you beat the owner at ACMA:GAME,
或是在ACMA：GAME恶魔游戏中 战胜持有者
devil's keys cannot be moved.
否则恶魔钥匙无法转移
So they'll use the game to take them from us?
所以他们利用锦标赛 来夺取我们的钥匙？
Probably. The Guide will take on
也许吧 最后引领者
whoever makes it to the end.
会和坚持到最后的胜者对决
Is this Guide even that good?
那个引领者有那么厉害吗？
The Guide?
引领者？
As the one with the most keys in the world.
他是目前世界上拥有最多钥匙的
His luck is boundless.
幸运持有者
You'll be like a lamb to the slaughter before him.
在他面前 你就是待宰的羔羊
We're all being used by Gungnir.
我们都被永恒之枪利用了
This whole tournament
整个锦标赛
is just part of his trap.
就是引领者的圈套
Ui.
初
The finals at the other two venues have been completed.
其他两个会场的决赛已经结束了
Everyone apart from the winner,
除了最后获胜的一人以外
friends and enemies alike, were executed by Gungnir.
其他人无论是敌是友 都被永恒之枪杀死了
What? Will the same happen to us?
什么？我们也会被杀死吗？
That's what they'll do if we hand over our lives?
这就是交出性命的意思吗？
The guide has planned the whole thing.
这全都是引领者策划的吗？
Well, well,
哎呀
thank you very much, Ui.
真是辛苦你了 初
You saved me the trouble of explaining.
省得我跟大家解释了
Hoshin,
崩心
where is The Guide?
引领者在哪里？
You want to meet him that much?
你这么想见他？
Just tell me.
快告诉我
Teruasa,
照朝
calm down.
冷静听我说
The Guide's true identity is－
引领者的真实身份是…
No, no, no!
不
Don't take all of the fun out of it.
直接说就没乐趣了
So,
所以
the Guide has arrived.
有请引领者大人
Father.
父亲
How?
怎么会？
NEXT EPISODE
（下集预告）
DIVE INTO THE FINAL CHAPTER
（最终章大曝光）
A fierce showdown between father and son.
父与子之间的激烈对决
I will remold this world into a better one.
我会将这个世界 打造成一个更好的世界
I will crush all of your ambitions.
我会粉碎你的所有企图
This is our fate, as father and son.
这是我们父子的宿命